Guide to the Angelo F. Semino Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Angelo F. Semino papers
1919-1937
SC0204
Semino, Angelo F.
3 Linear feet
Student notes from Stanford's early mechanical engineering and electrical engineering classes, 1919-21; typescript articles, charts, reports, and reprints (by Semino and others) largely pertaining to research done for Shell Oil Company of California, 1922-32; manuscript of THE OIL HEAT EXCHANGER by Semino and F.L. Kallum, 1925; and correspondence, 1934-37. Some materials relate to the Industrial Engineers, Inc. founded by four Stanford engineers in the 1930s. Also includes film on the Mayfield Development Project in Palo Alto.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Angelo F. Semino, 1979 and 1987.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Semino received his a.b. in mechanical engineering from Stanford University in 1922.
Description of the Collection
Student notes from Stanford's early mechanical engineering and electrical engineering classes, 1919-21; typescript articles, charts, reports, and reprints (by Semino and others) largely pertaining to research done for Shell Oil Company of California, 1922-32; manuscript of THE OIL HEAT EXCHANGER by Semino and F.L. Kallum, 1925; and correspondence, 1934-37. Some materials relate to the Industrial Engineers, Inc. founded by four Stanford engineers in the 1930s. Also includes film on the Mayfield Development Project in Palo Alto.
Access Terms
Industrial Engineers, Inc.; Kallum, Floyd Loren.; Semino, Angelo F.; Shell Oil Company.; Stanford University. School of Engineering. Students.; Palo Alto (Calif.); Petroleum engineering.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Class notes
    - M.E.33, Winter 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - M.E.32, Autumn 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - M.E.14, Winter 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mechanical Engineering Reports, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Electrical Engineering Reports, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reprints and articles
    - Shell Company of california, Gasoline Plants, Braun Equipment (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Charts of Experiments with oils (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles from Mechanical Engineering magazine, volumes 45-47 and 30, test sheets, temperature charts and diagrams for Shell Company of california (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Recent Research Work on the Internal-Combustion Engine" by Harry R. Ricardo in The Journal of the Society of Automative Engineers, Vol. X May, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Fractional Distillations of Fuel and How to Make Them" by P.S. Tice in Automative Industries, July 20, 1922; "Pressure-Temperature Chart for Hydrocarbon Vapors" by Edwin R. Cox in Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, Vol. 15, No.6, June 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Shell Company of california charts; "Profits Derives from Charcoal Plant Operation": Introduction and charts (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Tennination of Charcoal Tests for Gasoline" by F. L. Kallam, presentation for The American Society of Mechanical Engineers, June-July 1926; Description of the Stabilizer Yarhola Plant; Discussion on "The Termination of Charcoal Tests" by A.F. semino; Test on Stabilizer Equipment, Comar Oil Company, Gasoline Plant No. 1 Braman, Oklahoma, August 8, 1926; Blend curves chart; "Fundamentals of Heat Exchanger Design" by A.F. semino and F.L. Kallam (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Articles from Mechanical Engineering and National Petroleum News 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Articles, 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Charts for C.F. Braun and Co. and Shell Company of california (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Boiling Points of Paraffin Series; Boiler Test; Report on "A Detennination of the Boiling Points of Hydrocarbons under Pressure", "The Vapor Tensions of the Normal Paraffins" by A. A. Ashworth (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Heat of Vaporization of Petroleum Distillates" by J. D. Ruys (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Articles from Mechanical Engineering, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry and Refrigerating Engineering, 1924-1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Reprints and articles (Box 3)
    - Wessenden, E. A. and L. J. Bradford, "Tests on Welded Cylinders", Mechanical Engineering, Vol 44, No.9, pp. 581-592. Roark, R. J., "'The strength of Mechanically Welded Pressure Containers", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 44, No.4, pp. 225-230. Fish, G. D., "stresses and Defonnation in Flat Circular CYlinder Heads", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 44, No.3, pp. 165-170. "Oxy-Acetylene Welding in the Process Equipment Field", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol 31, No.9, pp. 341-346. "Arc Welding with Metallic Electrodes", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 32, No.5, pp. 206-208. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kallam, F. L., "'The Termination of Charcoal Tests", paper presented at the spring Meeting of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, June 28-July 1, 1926. Ramsey, W. K., "A Discussion of Draft Tube Designs", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 44, No.3, pp. 171-176. Kerr, S. L., "'The Moody Ej ector Turbine", Mechanical Engineer, Vol. 44, No.4, pp. 243-258. Lyon, G. E., "Flow in Canonical Draft Tubes of varying Angles", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 44, No.3, pp. 177-180. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1936 Correspondence - Oct. 9, Oct. 14, Oct. 28 (all with enclosures) - Nov. 12 and 14 1937 Correspondence - July 3, July 29, August 19, Sept. 2, Sept. 28, Oct. 13, Oct. 20, Oct. 25, Nov. 5 (all with enclosures) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Keenan, J. H., "A Revised Mollier Chart for Steam, Extended to the Critical Point", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 51, No. 2, pp. 109-115. Heck, R. C., "A General Steam Equation", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 51, No.2, pp. 116-122. Roe, J. W., "Principles of Jig and Fixture Practice", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 50, No. 12, pp. 909-913. BlLnn, W., "Mechanical Applications of Chromium Plating", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 50, No. 12, pp. 927-930. Waters, E. 0., "Graphical Methods for Least-Square Problems", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 50, No. 12, pp. 931-205. Other articles from Mechanical Engineering. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hill, P. W., Lyles, A. C. and P. Magruder, "Recommended Procedure for Gauging and Sampling Natural Gasoline", Petroleum World and Oil Age, June 1929, pp. 81-90. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Report of Test unit No.4: Ventura Gasoline Plant, Shell Company of california. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Classification of Accounts: Natural Gas and Gasoline Systems effective November 1, 1930, Shell Oil Company. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Vapor Pressure Experiments, Shell Oil Company. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Report of Test: O. C. Field Corporation Gasoline Plant Huntington Beach No.1 (Dec. 19, 1927), Shell oil Company of california. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Reporrt of Test unit No. 5 Ventura Gasoline Plant, Shell Company of california. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Estimate of Future Gas Production Dominguez Hill Field (February 15, 1927), Shell Company of california. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cement from oyster Shells", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 23, pp. 883-886. "Facts and Fakes Among Cracking Processes", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 19, pp. 737-742. Kirkpatrick, Sidney, "American Progress in Retorting oil Shale", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 20, pp. 770-774. "Oil-Shale Technology in the Making", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 18, pp. 688-692. "What about Oil Shale?", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 16, pp. 611-616. "Economic Problems in Oil-Shale Development", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 17, pp. 651-655. Sears, J. D., "Engineers and the American Petroleum Situation", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 47, No. I, pp. 5-12. Wallace, G. W., "Making Shale Oil in california", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 32, No.6, pp. 237-240. Brownlee, R. H., "Developing Modem Equipment for Cracking Petroleum", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 22, pp. 812-817. Morrell, J. C., "Operating a Modem Cracking Plant", Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, Vol. 31, No. 26, pp.l006-1010. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Koch, F. C., "construction and Operation of Bubble cap Towers", paper presented at the Western Petroleum Refiners Association, Jan. 17-18, 1927. Kallam, F. L., "'The Year's Progress in the california Natural Gasoline Industry", 'The Petroleum Engineer, 1931, pp.120-126. Eckart, W. R., "Specific Heat-Specific Gravity-Temperature Relations of Petroleum Oils", Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 47, No.7, pp. 535-544. Murray, I. L., "Graphical Solution of Problems Involving Solvent RecoveL}' by Scrubbing", Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, Vol. 22, No.2, pp. 165-167. Nelson, W. L., "'The Physical Constants of Petroleum Fractions", 'The Petroleum Engineer, May, 1931, pp. 41-42. "'The Properties of Petroleum Hydorcarbons", 'The Petroleum Engineer, February, 1931, pp. 97-104. Kemler, E., "A Study of the Data on the Flow of Fluids in Pipes", Transactions of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Dec. 1932. Brown, G. G., "Fuel Volatility, Engine Performance and Natural Gasoline", 'The Refiner and Natural Gasoline Manufacturer, Dec. 1926. Delaney, J. J., "Tests on Vapors Evolved During Partial Evaporation of Natural Gasoline", National Petroleum News, Oct. 5, 1927, pp. 55-56. Kaye, E., "By-Products Open Big Chemical Field For Natural Gasoline Makers", National Petroleum News, pp. 51-53. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Original Manuscript of The oil Heat Exchanger by A. F. semino and F .L. Kallam, long Beach, November 15, 1925. (87-001) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reports, articles and documents
    - Semino, A. F., Report of Preliminary Investigation on carbon Black Manufacture at Ventura Field. Loebel, A. and Verver, C. G., "The Badger Column as standard Apparatus for the Analysis of Crude Oils", Technical Report No. 12859, Laboratorium Van N. V. De Bataafsche Petroleum Maatschappij. Heltzel, W. G., "Fluid Flow and Friction in Pipe Lines", The Oil and Gas Journal, June 5, 1930, pp. T-203 to T-224. Sinuns, F. B., "A 100-Mile Natural Gasoline Transmission Line", Western Gas, pp. 20-2l. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Various Shell Oil Company (los Angeles) documents, dated - April 20, 1932 - April 19, 1932 - March I, 1932 - August 29, 1932 - october 3, 1933 - April II, 1933 - June 6, 1932 - July 29, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cooling Water by Exposure to Air Theo:ry (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Descriptive Report: Natural Gas and Gasoline Plants at long Beach, california, for the Shell Oil Company, December 1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Descriptive Report: Natural Gas and Gasoline Plants at Brea, california, for the Shell Oil Company, December 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Proceedings of The california Natural Gasoline Association, Volume III, and charts (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Reprints re: Natural Gas (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Gas and Gasoline Plants, L - Z (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Film on the Mayfield Development Project: Mayfield Mall and Alma Street development: reels A, B, C, D and 6 slides. (86-174) (Box 7)